When your Dad's an undertaker, your Mom's in heaven, and your Grandma's got a screw
loose...it's good to have a friend who understands you. Even if he is a boy.
My Girl is a comedy, drama film directed by Howard Zieff.
Vada Sultenfuss is obsessed with death.
Her mother is dead, and her father runs a funeral parlor.
She is also in love with her English teacher, and joins a
poetry class over the summer just to impress him.
Thomas J., her best friend, is "allergic to everything",
and sticks with Vada despite her hangups.
When Vada's father hires Shelly, and begins to fall for
her, things take a turn to the worse...
Vada Sultenfuss, played by Anna Chlumsky.
Thomas J. Sennett, played by Macaulay Culkin.
Harry Sultenfuss, played by Dan Aykroyd.
Shelly DeVoto, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
Phil Sultenfuss, played by Richard Masur.
Mr. Jake Bixler, played by Griffin Dunne.
My Girl is a 1991 American coming-of-age romantic comedy-drama film directed by Howard Zieff, written by Laurice Elehwany, and
starring Dan Aykroyd, Jamie Lee Curtis, Macaulay Culkin, and Anna Chlumsky in her first role in a major motion picture.
A book based on the film was written by Patricia Hermes.
The film tells the story of an 11-year-old girl living in
Madison, Pennsylvania, during the summer of 1972.
The film's title refers to the classic 1964 song of the same name by The
Temptations, which is also featured in the film's end credits.
The film was released by Columbia Pictures on November 27, 1991,
and grossed $121 million on a budget of $17 million.
A sequel, My Girl 2, was released in 1994.
The film explores themes of friendship, 1970s, beehive, remarriage, neighbor.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.